George S. Schuyler Papers
George S. Schuyler Papers
- Writings
  - Monographs mentioning George S. Schuyler and/or Philippa Schuyler
    - Fax, Elton C. Contemporary Black Leaders New York: Dodd, Mead, and Company, 1970; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Keeley, Joseph. The China Lobby Man: The Story of Alfred Kohlberg. New Rochelle: Arlington House, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Moon, Henry Lee. The Emerging Thought of W. E. B. Du Bois: Essays and Editorials from "The Crisis". New York: Simon and Schuster, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Monographs, other
    - Lane, Thomas A. The War for the World. San Diego, CA: Viewpoint Books, 1968 (Box 6)
    - McCallum, John D. The Story of Dan Lyons S.J.New York: Guild Books, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Ovington, Mary White. Half A Man: The Status of the Negro in New York. New York: American Century Series/Hills and Wang, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Newspapers
    - Scrapbooks, 1912-1931; 3 volumes; These scrapbooks were disassembled for microfilming. Material was distributed to various folders in the collection. See Related Material above for microfilm breakdown.
    - Clipping, 1928 (Box 6)
    - National News: The News Magazine of Colored America edited by George S. Schuyler, 1932, Feb-Apr; 3 folders, 10 issues (Box 6)
    - National News: The News Magazine of Colored America edited by George S. Schuyler, 1932, May-Jun; 2 folders, 6 issues (Box 7)
    - Scrapbooks, 1934-1947; These scrapbooks of newspaper clippings were disassembled for microfilming. Photocopies were made for the record, and original pages/material were distributed to various folders in the collection. See Related Material above for microfilm breakdown.
      - Photocopies of 3 scrapbooks, 1934-1935; 3 folders (Box 7)
      - Photocopy of scrapbook 'Serial Stories', 1936-1938 (Oversize 2)
      - Photocopies of 2 scrapbooks, 'Views and Reviews', 1935-1937; 2 folders (Oversize 3)
      - Photocopies of 2 scrapbooks, 'Views and Review', 1937-1943; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Photopcopy of scrapbook, 1940-1947 (Oversize 5)
      - Photocopy of scrapbook, 1944-1947 (Oversize 5)
    - Miscellaneous on Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1950; in English and German; 2 folders (Oversize 6)
    - Norwegian newsclippings, with typescript translations, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Scrapbooks, 1950-1955; 2 volumes; These scrapbooks were disassembled for microfilming. Material was distributed to various folders in the collection. See Related Material above for microfilm breakdown.
    - Clippings, 1953-1959 (Box 7)
    - Scrapbooks, 1957-1961; 3 volumes; These scrapbooks were disassembled for microfilming. Material was distributed to various folders in the collection. See Related Material above for microfilm breakdown.
    - Clippings, "The Literary Line," column from New Hampshire Manchester Union Leader, by George S. Schuyler, 1967-1971; 5 folders (Box 7)
    - Clippings, "The Literary Line," column from New Hampshire Manchester Union Leader, by George S. Schuyler, 1972-1975; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - News releases
    - Spadea syndicate, "For the Record", 1953; 1956,; 1959 (Box 8)
      May 15, 1953 "Negro Doctors Break Through"
      Jan 9, 1956 "New Black Nation Spells Trouble for West"
      Mar 26, 1956 "Casing an Uproar Over Campaign Gifts"
      Apr 13, 1959 "Is Socialism Strangling American Cities?"
    - North American Newspaper Alliance (NANA), 1966 (Box 8)
      Nov 19/20, 1966 "Negroes Overcoming Fears, Speak Out Against Militants"
      Dec 6, 1966 "Powell's School for Scandal Nearing End of It's Long Run"
    - North American Newspaper Alliance (NANA), 1967 (Box 8)
      Jan 7, 1967 "Reagan-Brooke Ticket in 1968 Would Put GOP in White House" (2 copies)
      Jan 13, 1967 "Adam Clayton Powell's Scandal Shows Risk of Black Racism" (2 copies)
      Jan 14, 1967 "Hollywood Everywhere: Brando Misses Paris Premiere of 'Countess from Hong Kong'"
      Feb 10, 1967 "Negro Conservative Asks: Do We Really Want Another Civil Rights 'Total War'?"
      Mar 29, 1967 "Explosive Cocktail: Luther King Mixes Bitter Potion of Negro Rights Plus 'Cong' Line"
      Apr 15, 1967 "Black Mahatma or Pink Napoleon?: Negro Conservative Finds King Almost as Diverting as Twiggy"
      Jul 1, 1967 "Can't Control Rioters: Rights Leaders are Victims of Own Frankenstein Monster"
      Jul 22, 1967 "Integration is 'Out': Black Nationalists May Take America Down Apartheid Path"
      Jul 29, 1967 "Put The Blame Where It Belongs: A Long, Hard Look at the Long, Hot Summer"
      Aug 12, 1967 "Black Racists Can Now Sit Back and Wait for Big Whitewash"
      Sep 16, 1967 "No Remorse for Riots?: A Few Words of Apology for America's Mid-summer Madness"
      Oct 14, 1967 "Cult of Blackness: Militant Negroes Travel the Marcus Garvey Trail"
      Dec 8, 1967 "More Strife Ahead: Rev. King's Christmastime Promise: Pandemonium by Cherry-Blossom Time"
    - North American Newspaper Alliance (NANA), 1968 (Box 8)
      Jan 27, 1968 "With Foundation Support: Black Revolutionists Need No Negro Dollars,"
      Mar 2, 1968 "Can Negro Business Community Survive Crime and Hot Summers?"
      Apr 6, 1968 "He Reaped the Whirlwind: A Cool and Critical Appraisal of Martin Luther King's Works"
      Jun 14, 1968 "Capitol Camp-in Washington Awaits 'Juneteenth' Day"
      Aug 10, 1968 "Negro History is 'In': Newest Educational Fad is 'Black Brainwashing'"
      Oct 9, 1968 "Campuses Calmly Await the Fourth R - Rioting
      Oct 26, 1968 "The Black-is-Beautiful Cult: Skeptical Negro Debunks the 'Natural Hero' Loo"
  - Periodicals with articles by George S. Schuyler
    - The African: Journal of African Affairs [bound volume], 1943-1949 (Box 9)
      Volume 2, no. 2 pp. 14-15, "Things of No Importance"; May 1943
      Volume 2, no. 3, p. 14 Jun 1943
      Volume 2, no. 4, pp. 14-15 Jul 1943
      Volume 2, no. 5 pp. 14-15 Aug 1943
      Volume 2, no. 6 p. 14; Sep 1943
      Volume 2, no. p. 14; Oct 1943
      Volume 2, no. p. 14; Nov/Dec 1943
      Volume 2, no. 9 p. 14; Jun 1944
      Volume 2, no. 10 p. 14 Aug 1944
      Volume 3, no. 1 p. 11, "It Happened in Africa" Apr 1945
      Volume 3, no. 3 p. 15 Jul/Aug 1945
      Volume 3, no. 4 pp. 15, 21 Oct 1945
      Volume 4, no. 1 pp. 10-11, 22 Jan 1946
      Volume 4, no. 2 pp. 18-20 Mar 1946
      Volume 4, no. 2 pp. 14, 15, 23 (number is printing error) May 1946
      Volume 4, no. 3 pp. 14-15 Jun 1946
      Volume 4, no. 4 pp. 14-15 Aug 1946
      Volume 4, no. 5 pp. 8, 14 Sep 1946
      Volume 4, no. 6 pp. 14, 17 Oct 1946
      Volume 4, no. 7 pp. 17, 20 Nov 1946
      Volume 5, no. 1 pp. 14-15 Jan 1947
      Volume 5, no. 5 pp. 18-19 May 1947
      Volume 5, no. 7 pp. 17-18 Aug 1947
      Also includes: Americas Vol. 1 no. 10, pp. 6-8, 41-42, "Haiti Looks Ahead" Dec 1949
    - The American Mercury [bound volume], 1927-1930 (Box 10)
      Vol. XII no. 48 pp. 385-392, "Our White Folks" Dec 1927
      Vol. XVII no. 68 pp. 469-476, "Keeping the Negro in His Place" Aug 1929
      Vol. XIX no. 74 pp. 212-220, "A Negro Looks Ahead" Feb 1930
      Vol. XX no. 80 pp. 423-432, "Traveling Jim Crow" Aug 1930 (2 copies: 1 bound, 1 individual copy)
      Vol. XXI no. 83 pp. 288-297, "Black Warriors" Nov 1930
    - The American Mercury [bound volume], 1931-1933 (Box 10)
      Vol. XXII no. 88 pp. 487-496, "Memoirs of a Pearl Diver" Apr 1931
      Vol. XXV no. 100 pp. 423-430, "Black America Begins to Doubt" Apr 1932
      Vol. XXVII no. 107 pp. 335-342, "Black Art" Nov 1932
      Vol. XXVII no. 107 pp. 147-156, "Uncle Sam's Black Stepchild" Jun 1933
    - The American Mercury, 1939; 1944,; 1949,; 1957 (Box 11)
      Vol. XLVII no. 186 pp. 176-181, "Negroes Reject Communism" Jun 1939
      Vol. LIX no. 252 pp. 686-691, "The Negro Problem Reaches a Crisis: B. More Race Riots Are Coming" Dec 1944
      Vol. LXVIII no. 306 pp. 663-670, "Jim Crow in the North" Jun 1949 (2 copies)
      Vol. LXXXIV no. 398 pp. 99-104, "The Negro Voter Comes of Age" Mar 1957
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Nov 1965-Sep 1967 (Box 11)
      Vol. VIII n. 10 pp. 11-16, "For America: Let Negroes Give Thanks" Nov 1965
      Vol. IX no. 1 pp. 15-21, "Journalism: The Wagon That Broke Down" Jan 1966
      Vol. IX no. 3 pp. 13-16, "The Farmer: Johnson's Taming of the Shrews" Mar 1966
      Vol. X no. 2 pp. 29-34, "The Hangover: Negro Masses are Turning From the Revolution" Mar 1967
      Vol. X no. 4 pp. 23-29, "Pastorniks: An Angry Essay by a Man of Faith" May 1967
      Vol. X no. 7 pp. 51-52, "From Africa" Sep 1967
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Oct 1967-Mar 1968 (Box 11)
      Vol. X no. 8 pp. 53-54, "From Africa, and 87-92, Columnists: Style as the Great Journalistic Casualty" Oct 1967
      Vol. X no. 9 pp. 25-30, "Babbit: Requiem for an American" and pp. 55-56, "From Africa" Nov 1967
      Vol. X no. 10 pp. 57-58, "From Africa and pp. 81-86, "Filthopolis: What's Wrong with Our Cities" Dec 1967
      Vol. XI no. 1 pp. 25-31, "Hellfare: A Look at the Welfare Racket" and pp. 55-56, "From Africa" Jan 1968
      Vol. XI no. 2 pp. 27-32, "Acadummies: Socialism's Failure in Education" and pp. 55-56, "From Africa" and pp. 107-108, (review) The Crisis of the Negro Intellectual by Harold Cruse and pp. 113, "Henry L. Mencken" Feb 1968
      Vol. XI no. 3 pp. 57-58, "From Africa" and pp. 103-112, "Mr. Schuyler: The Reds and I" Mar 1968
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Apr 1968-Oct 1968 (Box 11)
      Vol. XI no. 4 pp. 55-56, "From Africa" and pp. 73, "They Paused to Remark" Apr 1968
      Vol. XI no. 5 pp. 55-56, "From Africa" May 1968
      Vol. XI no. 6 pp. 65-66, "From Africa" Jun 1968
      Vol. XI no. 7 pp. 77-87, "Middle East: Communists Score Major Victories" and 88, "They Paused to Remark" and pp. 173-176, "Our Cover: Anti-Communist Moise Tshombe" Jul/Aug 1968
      Vol. XI no. 8 pp. 63-64, "From Africa" Sep 1968
      Vol. XI no. 9 pp. 47-48, "From Africa" Oct 1968
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Nov 1968-Apr 1969 (Box 11)
      Vol. XI no. 10 pp. 45-46, "A Red Africa?: Communists are After Key African Ports" Nov 1968
      Vol. XI no. 11 pp. 67-68, "Phony Tears: Africa's Nationalist Hypocrisy" Dec 1968
      Vol. XII no. 1 pp. 21-30, "The Fall: From Decency to Degradation" and pp. 65-66, "Biafra: That Grisly War in Nigeria" Jan 1969
      Vol. XII no. 2 pp. 75-76, "Where Oil Is: Propaganda, Genocide, and Biafra's Oil" Feb 1969
      Vol. XII no. 3 pp. 21-24, "Bright Star: George S. Schuyler Reviews Philippa Schuyler" and pp. 41-42, "Mini-states: The Problem of All Those Lilliputs" Mar 1969
      Vol. XII no. 4 pp. 71-72, "Portugal: Enjoying the Last Laugh in Africa" Apr 1969
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, May-1969-Nov 1969 (Box 12)
      Vol. XII no. 5 pp. 77-78, "African Unity: A Look at Some Vanishing Fictions" May 1969
      Vol. XII no. 6 pp. 73-74, "In Lilliput: The Republic of Equatorial Guinea" Jun 1969
      Vol. XII no. 7 pp. 97-108, "Africa: The Red and the Black" Jul/Aug 1969
      Vol. XII no. 8 pp. 37-38, "The Sudan: Shades of 'Chinese' Gordon!" Sep 1969
      Vol. XII no. 9 pp. 85-87 (review) On Communism by J. Edgar Hoover and pp. 93-94 (review) Three- Fifths of a Man by Floyd McKissick. Oct 1969
      Vol. XII no. 10 pp. 23-27, "Spirit of '76: The Declaration of Independence on Broadway" Nov 1969
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Jan 1970-Jun 1970 (Box 12)
      Vol. XIII no. 1 pp. 17-18, "Saint Martin?: The Martin Luther King Memorial" Jan 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 2 pp. 27-28, "Bad Pennies: My, How They Do Run" Feb 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 3 pp. 15-16, "Fleet Ralph: The Reverand Abernathy is Tired of Running" Mar 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 4 pp. 23-25, "General Patton: A Film Salute to an American Rebel" Apr 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 5 Cover, inside cover, p. 78, "They Paused to Remark" May 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 6 pp. 27-28, "The Uptopians: And the Gurgle and Glow of Missionism" and 72, "They Paused to Remark" Jun 1970
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Jul/Aug 1970-Jul/Aug 1971 (Box 12)
      Vol. XIII no. 7 pp. 45-60, "Africa: The Comrades Beat the Bushes" Jul/Aug 1970
      Vol. XIII no. 10 pp. 17-22, "Cowardice: And the Attack on American Morality" and 71, "Bullets..." Nov 1970
      Vol. XIV no. 1 pp. 76, "They Paused to Remark" Jan 1971
      Vol. XIV no. 7 pp. 31-36, "Middle East: It Is All Sinking in a Red Sea" Jul/Aug 1971
    - American Opinion: An Informal Review, Mar 1972-Jul/Aug 1973 (Box 12)
      Vol. XV no. 3 pp. 81-85, H. L. Mencken: Inconoclast From Baltimore by Douglas C. Stenerson reviewed by Medford Evans, mentions George S. Schuyler's relationship with Mar 1972
      Vol. XV no. 7 pp. 71-80, "The Movers: Departments of H. U. D. and Transportation" Jul/Aug 1972
      Vol. XVI no. 2 pp. 31-36, "Malcolm X: Better to Memorialize Benedict Arnold" Feb 1973
      Vol. XVI no. 7 pp. 67-80, "Africa: Red, White, and Black" Jul/Aug 1973
    - The American Spectator, 1934 (Oversize 2)
      Vol. II no. 22 1-2, "Sam Leibowitz: Jonah in Modern Dress" Aug 1934 [with photocopies]
    - Common Ground, 1943 (Box 13)
      Vol. III no. 3 (Spring ) 41-44, "Vacation Daze" 1943
    - The Crisis [bound volume], 1932-1945; 1949 (Box 13)
      Volume 41 no. 1 pp. 456, 472, "The Negro Co-operative League" Jan 1932
      Volume 41 no. 9 pp. 258-260, 274, "To Boycott or Not to Boycott?" with Vere E. Johns Sep 1934
      Volume 42 no. 1 p. 12, "Scripture for Lynchers" Jan 1935
      Volume 42 no. 5 pp. 134-135, 148-149, "Which Way Out for the Negro? The Separate State Hokum" May 1935
      Volume 42 no. 5 duplicate May 1935
      Volume 43 no. 10 pp. 302-306, "Freedom of the Press in Mississippi" Oct 1936
      Volume 43 no. 11 pp. 328-329, "New Job Frontiers for Negro Youth" Nov 1936
      Volume 44 no. 4 pp. 102-103, "Do We Really Want Equality?" Apr 1937
      Volume 44 no. 7 pp. 205-206, "Not Gone With the Wind" Jul 1937
      Volume 44 no. 10 pp. 308-309, "A Treatise on Mulattoes" Oct 1937
      Volume 44 no. 11 pp. 327-328, 347, "Reflections on Negro Leadership" Nov 1937
      Volume 45 no. 8 pp. 255-257, 274-275, "The Rise of the Black Internationale" Aug 1938
      Volume 45 no. 9 pp. 298-299, "The Nation Pays Tribute: James Weldon Johnson" Sep 1938
      Volume 47 no. 5 pp. 143, 157-158, "Craftsmen in the Blue Grass" May 1940
      Volume 47 no. 6 pp. 170-171, 178, "Garner - At Home" Jun 1940
      Volume 47 no. 7 pp. 219, "Letters from Readers" Jul 1940
      Volume 48 no. 12 pp. 384, 389, "Hitler Without Hitler" Dec 1941
      Volume 49 no. 6 pp. 194-195, "American Caught Up With Him: The Story of Lucky Robert's 'Moonlight Cocktail'" Jun 1942
      Volume 50 no. 11 pp. 328-329, 344, "A Long War Will Aid the Negro" Nov 1943
      Volume 52 no. 1 pp. 25-26 (review) Top Hats and Tom-toms by Elizabeth Dearmon Furbay Jan 1945
      Volume 56 no. 1 p. 3 (credits) Jan 1949
    - The Crisis, 1951; 1955,; 1959 (Box 13)
      Volume 58 no. 3 pp. 163-164, "Forty Years of 'The Crisis'" Mar 1951
      Volume 62 no. 5 pp. 314-315 (review) Black Moses: The Story of Marcus Garvey and the Universal Negro Improvement Association by Edmund D. Cronon, and pp. 316-317 (review by Philippa Schuyler) America's Music: From the Pilgrim to the Present by Gilbert Chase. May 1955
      Volume 76 no. 5 pp. 207-210, by Josephine Schuyler, "Race, Diet, and Intelligence" May 1969
    - Duke, Volumes 1-6, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Ebony and Topaz: A Collectanea 1927, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Farmand, pp. 25-26, "Intervju Meden Neger Redaktor" and miscellaneous materials. Jan 1951, See Norwegian newsclippings.
    - The Freeman, duplicates of Nov 19, 1951 and May 3, 1954 issues (see bound issues below) (Box 13)
    - Globe [MISSING Dec 2018], 1937
      Vol. 1 no. 1 pp. 56-60, "Woman Palavar" Mar 1937
      Vol. 1 no. 4 pp. 10-16, "Monrovia Moocheson" Jul 1937
      Vol. 1 no. 3 pp. 71-76, "The Lord's Work" Jun 1937
    - Human Events, 1959; 1968 (Box 13)
      Vol. XVI no. 16 p. 2, "Where Communists Fear to Tread: Why the Reds Are Out to Get Trujillo" Apr 22, 1959 - reprint (2 copies)
      Vol. XVIII no. 11 p. 10 "Can Negro Business Survive Summer of Riots?" Mar 16, 1968
      "New Educational Fad: Will Black History Really Be Brainwashing?" Aug 24, 1968 - reprint
    - Human Events, 1969 (Oversize 7)
      Vol. XXIX no. 15 p. 44, "Greetings on Human Event's 25th Anniversary" Apr 12, 1969
    - Interracial Review, 1943 (Box 13)
      "The Education of White Folks," 2 pp Jul 1943 - reprint
    - Manion Forum, 1968 (Box 13)
      no. 714, 4 pp, "Step by Step: Distinguished Journalist Views and Reviews Unfolding Tragedy" Jun 9, 1968 (2 copies)
    - The Messenger: World's Greatest Negro Monthly, 1925 (Oversize 7)
      Vol. VII no. 1 pp. 21-23, "Interviews with Actors" and pp. 35-36, "Shafts and Darts With Theophilus Lewis" Jan 1925
    - Modern Age: A Quarterly Review, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
      Vol. 11 no. 3 1967 (Summer 1967) pp. 320-323 (review) "The Negro's Dilemma" Negro Social and Political Thought by Howard Brotz, Freedom - When? by James Farmer (both issue and duplicate pages from the issue)
      [v.11 no. 4 1967] (Fall 1967) pp. 414-417 (review) "Black History" The Secret City: A History of Race Relations in the Nation's Capitol by Constance M. Green, NAACP: A History of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People by Charles F. Kellogg. (pages only - no issue)
      Vol. 12 no. 2 1968 (Spring ) pp. 200-201 (review) "Black Power Syndrome" Black Power and Urban Unrest by Nathan Wright Jr., Black Power by Stokley Carmichael and Charles V. Hamilton.
    - Negro Digest, 1940; 1943-1944 (Box 13)
      Vol. 1 no. 4 pp. 67-72, "Who Is Negro, Who Is White?" Nov 1940
      Vol. 1 no. 7 pp. 69-72, "Vacation Daze" May 1943 (2 copies)
      Vol. II no. 5 pp. 11-12, "My Most Humiliating Jim Crow Experience" Mar 1944
      Vol. II no. 8 pp. 43-45, "Should Negroes in the South Migrate North?: Yes" Jun 1944 (2 copies)
    - Negro Digest, 1944-1946 (Box 13)
      Vol. III no. 2 pp. 60-64, "Have Communists Quit Fighting for Negro Rights? Yes" Dec 1944
      Vol. III no. 7 pp. 52-54, "What the Negro Thinks of the South" May 1945
      Vol. IV no. 9 pp. 1-6, "Do Negroes Want to be White?" Jul 1946; includes article on pp. 61-65 by Josephine Schuyler, "17 Years of Mixed Marriage"
    - Negro Digest, 1947; 1949 (Box 14)
      Vol. V no. 4 pp. 86-90, "Was Booker T. Wrong?" Feb 1947 (2 copies)
      Vol. V no. 11 pp. 28-32, "What's Wrong With the NAACP?" Sep 1947 (2 copies)
      Vol. VII no. 7 pp. 52-57, "Color Lines In Latin America" May 1949 (2 copies)
      Vol. VII no. 10 pp. 37-42, "Race in Rio," by Charles Anderson Gauld Aug 1949
    - Negro Digest, 1950-1951 (Box 14)
      originally bound together, but the binding has separated and issues are foldered instead of being bound
      Vol. VIII no. 7 pp. 3-7, "What's Wrong With Negro Authors" May 1950
      Vol. IX no. 8 pp. 52-56, "Why I Want to Stay in America" Jun 1951
      Vol. X no. 1 pp. 40-43, "Are Negroes More Prejudiced Than Whites?" Nov 1951 (2 copies)
    - Phylon, 1950 (Box 14)
      Fourth Quarter 1950 "The Van Vechten Revolution", reprint of article
    - The Priest, 1967 (Box 14)
      Vol. 23 no. 6 pp. 455-460, "All God's Chillun Got Wings" Jul 1967
    - Reader's Digest, 1951 (Box 14)
      Vol. 59 no. 351 pp. 61-63, "The Phantom American Negro" Jul 1951 (2 copies); includes bound international editions of the article and letter from De Witt Wallace, editor at Reader's Digest
    - Reader's Digest, 1951 (Box 15)
      "The Phantom American Negro" 1951
    - Review of the News, 1967 (Box 15)
      Volume 3 no. 20 pp. 27-32, "Analysis: The New Southern Africa" May 17, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 24 pp. 27-32, "Analysis: The Perils of Provocation" Jun 14, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 29 pp. 27-32, "Analysis: The Supreme Court, Again" Jul 19, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 33 pp. 27-32, "Analysis: Rumpelstiltskin Unlimited" Aug 16, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 38 pp. 15-20, "Analysis: Black Power Apartheid" Sep 20, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 42 pp. 15-20, "Analysis: Love's Labor Lost in Mississippi" Oct 18, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 46 pp. 15-20, "Analysis: School for Treason" Nov 15, 1967
      Volume 3 no. 51 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: The Mini-Crusaders" Dec 20, 1967
    - Review of the News, 1968; 2 folders (Box 15)
      Volume 4 no. 3 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: Facing Open-Housing" Jan 17, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 7 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: A Closet Full of Skeletons" Feb 14, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 12 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: The Desperados" Mar 20, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 16 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: Tempests in the Coffee-pot" Apr 17, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 20 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: Toward a Long, Cool Summer" May 15, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 26 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: Collective Guilt" Jun 26, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 29 pp. 15-20, "Analysis: The Great Ghetto Swindle" Jul 17, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 33 pp. 17-22, "Analysis: A Massacre of Fictions" Aug 14, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 38 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: Chicago: Ominous Portent" Sep 18, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 42 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: Narcotics, Anyone?" Oct 16, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 45 pp. 23-27, "Report!: American Negro Leaders", by Kent Courtney on George S. Schuyler. Nov 6, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 47 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: Drive for Discrimination" Nov 20, 1968
      Volume 4 no. 51 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: NACCP: A Great Light Dawns" Dec 18, 1968
    - Review of the News, 1969 (Box 16)
      Volume 5 no. 4 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: How Black Your Alma Mater?" Jan 22, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 8 pp. 17-22, "Report!: Who's Loony Now?" Feb 19, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 11 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: The Semantic Jungle" Mar 12, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 22 pp. 25-30, "Report!: Orphans of the Storm" May 28, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 29 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: No Hidin' Place" Jul 16, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 32 pp. 17-22, "Report!: Cinema Sodom" Aug 6, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 34 pp. 25-30, "Analysis: Dangerous Games" Aug 20, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 38 pp. 21-26, "Analysis: Why Not Detention?" Sep 17, 1969 (2 copies)
      Volume 5 no. 39 pp. 24-26, "Red Sea Vacuum" Sep 24, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 44 pp. 17-24, "Analysis: More Nerve Than Tracy!" Oct 29, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 47 pp. 17-26, "Analysis: The 'Black Capitalism' Hoax" Nov 19, 1969
      Volume 5 no. 52 pp. 17-26, "Analysis: The Foresight Saga" Dec 24, 1969
    - Review of the News, 1970 (Box 16)
      Volume 6 no. 3 pp. 17-26, "Analysis: Who Should Vote" Jan 21, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 7 pp. 17-24, "Analysis: Friends of Foes" Feb 18, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 11 pp. 17-26, "Analysis: Mortarboard Madness" Mar 18, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 23 pp. 29-32, "Analysis: Reincarnation of the Jungle" Jun 10, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 27 pp. 33-40, "Why Not Vouchers for Private Schools?" Jul 8, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 41 pp. 31-40, "The Monster That Devoured Cleveland" Oct 14, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 47 pp. 35-44, "Mao Will Push Dope Via Canada" Nov 25, 1970
      Volume 6 no. 52 pp. 23-30, "George S. Schuyler" Dec 30, 1970
    - Review of the News, 1971; 2 folders (Box 16)
      Volume 7 no. 4 pp. 33-44, "Phantasm of the Pixilated Pedagogues" Jan 27, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 12 pp. 35-44, "Mau-Mauing" Mar 24, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 20 pp. 35-44, "Snooping" May 19, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 24 pp. 23-32, "Gradueaten" Jun 16, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 25 pp. 23-32, "Fellowship of Reconcilliation" by E. Merrill Rogt Jun 23, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 29 pp. 42-44, "Prisoners" Jul 21, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 34 pp. 35-42, "Ankle-bite" Aug 25, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 39 pp. 23-32, "Krazy Kats" Sep 29, 1971
      Volume 7 no. 42 pp. 25-26, "The Arts" Oct 20, 1971 (Succeeding articles are "The Arts" column)
      Volume 7 no. 43 pp. 27-28 Oct 27, 1971